{
 "subject": "civics",
 "lesson": "l01",
 "grade": "c4",
 "quests": [
	{
		"id": 1,
		"question": "The Governor of a state is appointed by",
		"options": {
			"a": "President",
			"b": "Vice President",
			"c": "Prime Minister",
			"d": "Chief Minister"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 2,
		"question": "The State Council Minsters is headed by",
		"options": {
			"a": "The Governor",
			"b": "Chief Minister",
			"c": "Speaker",
			"d": "Home Minister"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 3,
		"question": "Who can summon and prorogue the sessions of the State legislature?",
		"options": {
			"a": "Home Minister",
			"b": "President",
			"c": "Speaker",
			"d": "The Governor"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	},
	{
		"id": 4,
		"question": "Who does not participate in the appointment of the High Court Judge?",
		"options": {
			"a": "Governor",
			"b": "Chief Minister",
			"c": "Chief Justice of the High Court",
			"d": "President of India"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 5,
		"question": "The age of retirement of the Judges of the High Court is",
		"options": {
			"a": "62",
			"b": "64",
			"c": "65",
			"d": "58"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 6,
		"question": "Governor",
		"options": {
			"a": "Lower House62",
			"b": "Nominal Head",
			"c": "Upper House",
			"d": "Real Head"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 7,
		"question": "Chief Minister",
		"options": {
			"a": "Lower House62",
			"b": "Nominal Head",
			"c": "Upper House",
			"d": "Real Head"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	},
	{
		"id": 8,
		"question": "Legislative Assembly",
		"options": {
			"a": "Lower House62",
			"b": "Nominal Head",
			"c": "Upper House",
			"d": "Real Head"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 9,
		"question": "Legislative Council",
		"options": {
			"a": "Lower House62",
			"b": "Nominal Head",
			"c": "Upper House",
			"d": "Real Head"	
		},
		"answer": "c"
	},
	{
		"id": 10,
		"question": "Chief Minister is the chief administrator of the State.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 11,
		"question": "The Governor nominates two members of the Anglo- Indian Community to Legislative Assembly.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 12,
		"question": "The number of judges in the High Courts is not uniform and fixed.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "a"
	}
	}
  ]
}